A Register of the Albert J. and Roberta Wohlstetter Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1936-1996. (Box 62)
  - Writings., See also Roberta Wohlstetter File
    - Bishops, Statesmen, and Other Strategists on the Bombing of Innocents, 1983
      - Translations
        - German, Pro Pace, 1984 (Folder 182: 3)
      - Responses from others (Folder 182: 4-9)
      - Replies by Albert Wohlstetter, including to Theodore Draper (Box-folder 183: 1-5)
    - "Still Further on MAC #3,", 1983 July 27. (Folder 183: 6)
    - "Morality and Deterrence," Commentary, 1983 December. (Folder 183: 7)
      Printed copy. Includes a letter from Caspar Weinberger
    - Paper, Chicago, 1984?
      - Background materials (Folder 183: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 183: 9)
    - "Armenian Terror as a Special Case of International Terror" (with Nancy Virts), 1984 April 12
      - Background materials (Folder 183: 10)
      - Notes (Folder 183: 11)
      - Typescript (Folder 183: 12)
    - Comments on Trulock and Gouré, "Soviet Perspectives on Limited Nuclear Warfare: Characteristics, Options, and Objectives,", 1984 July 9. (Folder 183: 13)
    - "Strategic Modernization, Arms Agreements and Reduced Reliance on Nuclear Brute Force" (possible title), 1984 September 6
      - Background materials (Folder 183: 14)
      - Notes (Folder 183: 15)
      - Outline and typescript., See also 1984 December (Box-folder 184: 1)
    - "Killer Satellites that Would Start a War by Computer?", 1984 October 15
      - Background materials (Folder 184: 2)
      - Typescript (Folder 184: 3)
    - "Nuclear Winter and Other Recent Versions of the Apocalypse,", 1984 November? (Folder 184: 4)
    - "Acheson and the North Atlantic Defense Committee in 1949 on NATO Reliance Strategic Nuclear Force,", 1984 November 8. (Folder 184: 5)
    - "Power for Gulf Contingencies,", 1984 November 19. (Folder 184: 6)
    - "Notes on Arms Agreements and the Problems of Enforcement" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1984 December
      - Background materials (Folder 184: 7)
      - Notes (Folder 184: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 184: 9-10)
      - Response to Bud McFarlane (Folder 184: 11)
    - "Nuclear Winter and the Other Limits of MAD's Incoherence,", 1984 December 18. (Box-folder 185: 1)
    - "On Disconfirmability and Arms Control: A Karl Popper Sort of Observation on the Troubles with 'Verification',", 1984 December 20. (Folder 185: 2)
    - "On the Seeming Insignificance of Violations During Creep-Out,", 1984 December 20. (Folder 185: 3)
    - "Are the Media Penetrable: Notes on Filtering the News on SDI for the Coming Arms Negotiations,", 1984 December 21. (Folder 185: 4)
    - "Optimistic Pessimism: The French and Other MAD Views of War,", 1984 December 25. (Folder 185: 5)
    - "On Not Killing Anybody 'Per Se': Complementary Hypocrisies of Targeteers and MAD Arms Controllers,", 1984 December 26. (Folder 185: 6)
    - "Bethe 1954 against Mutual Destruction Capabilities,", 1984 December 27. (Folder 185: 7)
    - "Persuading the Soviets to Let Us Live Too: Kissinger and Nitze, Winter 1984/1985,", 1984 December 28. (Folder 185: 8)
    - Foreword to Soviet Nationalities in Strategic Perspective, edited by Enders Wimbush, 1985
      - Typescript (Folder 185: 9)
      - Printed copy (Folder 185: 10)
    - "Did the Soviet Deployment of MIRVs Follow an 'Iron Law' of Soviet Evasive Reaction to the Action of Arms Agreements?", 1985 January 2. (Folder 185: 11)
    - "NATO Counterattacks on the Ground Inside WTO: Comments on Huntington, Dean, and Wartime Dissidence in the WTO,", 1985 January 4. (Folder 185: 12)
    - Topics for General William Odom, 1985 January 11. (Folder 185: 13)
    - "The Global Non-Effects of Non-Global Wars,", 1985 January 16. (Folder 185: 14)
    - "Virtual Redundancy Suffices for Preferential Active Defense,", 1985 January 21. (Folder 185: 15)
    - "Nuclear Winter Theorists Say Our Retaliation Would Be Suicidal, but Luckily, so Would His Attack,", 1985 January 25. (Folder 185: 16)
    - "With Nuclear Winter, the Attacker May Have to Fear the Defenses Success Less than Its Catastrophic Failure,", 1985 January 25. (Folder 185: 17)
    - "Have the Members of the Politburo Ever Really Worried About an Unprovoked U.S. First Strike?", 1985 March 4. (Folder 185: 18)
    - "U.S. First Strike: S.U. Disinformation and U.S. Media Confusion,", 1985 March 5. (Folder 185: 19)
    - "Soviet 'Self-Deterrence,' the SecDef Nuclear Winter Report and the Washington Post,", 1985 March 7. (Folder 185: 20)
    - "Bohlen 1952 on Wartime Strains on Soviet Control of Its Satellites,", 1985 March 12. (Folder 185: 21)
    - "Soviet 'Self-Deterrence' and Science Magazine,", 1985 March 12. (Folder 185: 22)
    - "Special Evaluation for the NSC in 1953 Which Assumed Attacks So Large Against SAC, Cities, and Everything That They Didn't Hurt SAC Much,", 1985 March 12. (Folder 185: 23)
    - "Carl Sagan on the Comforts of Total Ruin,", 1985 March 13. (Folder 185: 24)
    - "Illustrating Karl Popper's Point in Connection with Violations of Agreements,", 1985 March 13. (Folder 185: 25)
    - "Sagan vs. Fermi on the Evils of Large City-Destroying Bombs in Contrast to Small Nuclear Weapons,", 1985 March 14. (Folder 185: 26)
    - "Uncertainties, Suicidal Choices, MAD and Nuclear Winter,", 1985 April 15. (Folder 185: 27)
    - "Deterring an Attack Entails Being Able to Respond to It Without Committing Suicide,", 1985 April 21. (Folder 185: 28)
    - "Western Preferred Huge Soviet and U.S. Attacks,", 1985 April 21. (Folder 185: 29)
    - "SAC Test 1957 of Alert Bomber Response – Only 'Fail-Unsafe',", 1985 April 29. (Folder 185: 30)
    - "Dissent in the Soviet Empire: Strategic Implications," based in part on a foreword to Soviet Nationalities in Strategic Perspective, edited by Enders Wimbush, 1985 May 28. (Folder 185: 31)
    - "Joint Maximum and Minimum Restraints on the Offense,", 1985 June 13. (Folder 185: 32)
    - "On Spies and Détente,", 1985 June 16
      - Background materials (Folder 185: 33)
      - Typescript (Folder 185: 34)
    - Between an Unfree World and None: Increasing Our Choices, 1985
      - Correspondence (Folder 185: 35)
      - Notes (Folder 185: 36)
      - Typescript (Folder 185: 37)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 186: 1-8)
      - Galley (Folder 186: 9)
      - Printed copies, including version in Foreign Affairs, 1985 Summer (Folder 186: 10-11)
    - "A Space Agreement Must Be Useful and Enforceable" (with Brian Chow), 1985 July 2. (Folder 186: 12)
    - "An Anti-Satellite Agreement To Help Protect Satellites" (with Brian Chow), 1985 July 15. (Folder 186: 13)
    - "Die Turkei und die Sicherung der Interessen der NATO,", 1985
      - Background materials (Folder 186: 14)
      - Correspondence (Folder 186: 15)
      - Typescript. English translation (Folder 186: 16)
      - Printed copy of version in Europa Archiv, 1985 August 25, and review (Box-folder 187: 1)
    - "The United States and Elliot Cohen's Three Challenges,", 1985 September 4. (Folder 187: 2)
    - "Beyond Simple Attack and Retaliation,", 1985 October 17. (Folder 187: 3)
    - "The ABM Treaty as Ratifying Laws of Physics,", 1985 December 17. (Folder 187: 4)
    - "Au delà de la stratégie du pire," Commentaire, Winter 1985-1986
      - Typescript (Folder 187: 5-9)
      - Printed copy (Folder 187: 10)
    - "Parallel Between the Right Way to Reply Both to Terrorists and to Military Attack: A Possible Idea for the President's Speech on Defense Uniting Several of His Recent Remarks and His Deepest Concerns,", 1986 January 22
      - Background materials (Folder 187: 11)
      - Typescript (Folder 187: 12)
    - "Political Decisions to Do Something Positive Are More Likely if Negative Restraints Limit the Risks: Fail-Safe, PALS, Selectivity, Dudding of Unreliable Weapons, etc., etc.,", 1986 February 3. (Folder 187: 13)
    - "The Theory of Deterrence as Comparative Risk Led to an Early Stress on the Protecting of C3I: Minimum Deterrence Theory and MAD Led to Its Neglect,", 1986 February 5. (Folder 187: 14)
    - "Do We Really Want the Soviets to Be Able to Destroy Us: How McNamara Changed the Idea of Stability that Had Been Contained in The 'Delicate Balance',", 1986 February 7. (Folder 187: 15)
    - "Midgetman, First-Strike Instability, 'Conservatives' and 'Liberals',", 1986 February 10. (Folder 187: 16)
    - "Retargeting in Contrast to Preplanned Missions?", 1986 February 10. (Folder 187: 17)
    - "Packet Switching,", 1986 February 28
      - Background materials (Folder 187: 18)
      - Typescript (Folder 187: 19)
    - Comments on Bill G's letter to the Los Angeles Times, 1986 March 3. (Folder 187: 20)
      Notes and related materials
    - "Comments on Multiple Satellite System (MSS) Material Sent by Zraket and SPACECOM,", 1986 March 26. (Folder 187: 21)
    - "On the Genesis of Nuclear Strategy," a 1968 letter with additional material and comment by James Digby and Arthur Steiner and a note by Michael Howard, 1986. (Folder 187: 22)
    - "New Directions for Arms Agreements?", 1986 April 10
      - Notes (Folder 187: 23)
      - Typescript (Folder 187: 24)
    - "Giving a Capability: Components of ABM Contrasted with Backfire Bombers, Aegis, etc.,", 1986 April 16. (Folder 187: 25)
    - "Comments on Project Vista and Nuclear Weapons in Europe: A Commentary on David Elliot's Paper Presented on 1986 April 30 at California Seminar,", 1986 May 6. (Box-folder 188: 1)
    - "Self-Defense Zones in Space" (with Brian G. Chow), 1986 July. (Folder 188: 2)
    - "Self-Deterrence, Self-Distrust, and 'Use Never',", 1986 July 2. (Folder 188: 3)
    - "Would Current Proposals for Agreements Delay or Destroy SDI?", 1986 July 10. (Folder 188: 4)
    - "A Point Made by Albert Wohlstetter During a Luncheon with Dr. Anthony Iorillo at Space Communications Group of Hughes-Aircraft Company on July 17" (written up by Brian Chow?), 1986 July 17. (Folder 188: 5)
    - "Preferring the 'Worst Case' for Strategic Air Command (SAC),", 1986 August 5
      - Background materials (Folder 188: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 188: 7)
    - "Providing for Continuity and Making It Evident" (with Roberta Wohlstetter and Richard Brody), 1986 August 18
      - General (Folder 188: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 188: 9)
    - "Trends, Lags in Deployment, and the Future of Technologies of Control,", 1986 August 21. (Folder 188: 10)
    - "La minaccia sovietica," MondOperaio, 1986 August-September
      - Galley (Folder 188: 11)
      - Printed copy (Folder 188: 12)
    - "Testing, SDI, and the Luddite Trend in Arms Control,", 1986 September 16
      - Background materials (Folder 188: 13)
      - Typescript (Folder 188: 14)
    - "Flat Earthers and the Claim that MAD Is only a Condition, not a Policy,", 1986 September 25. (Folder 188: 15)
    - "Other Versions of Defense without Offense: The Savage Danes and Other Western Menaces Reassure the Soviets,", 1986 September 29. (Folder 188: 16)
    - "Boris Yeltsin as Abraham Lincoln,", 1986 October. (Folder 188: 17)
    - "Has There Been a Slow-Down in Military Innovation since the 1950s?", 1986 November 2. (Box-folder 189: 1)
    - "More on MAD as a Condition, not a Policy,", 1986 November 2. (Folder 189: 2)
    - "The Nuclear Arms Race after Reykjavik and the Newly Noticed Problems for the West with Nuclear Disarmament,", 1986 November 2. (Folder 189: 3)
    - "Pure Defense, Pure Offense and the Footless Effort to Make 'First Strike Theoretically Impossible' for Either Side,", 1986 November 2. (Folder 189: 4)
    - "The Necessity of Mixed Offense and Defense to Deter or Combat Chemical Attack,", 1986 November 3. (Folder 189: 5)
    - "Terrorism and Divisions in the Alliance,", 1986 November 3. (Folder 189: 6)
    - "Alvin Bernstein on the Lack of a U.S. Strategy for Low Intensity War,", 1986 November 10. (Folder 189: 7)
    - "Note on ILS and the Democratic Leadership Council's Defending America (Sam Nunn, Les Aspin, Al Gore),", 1986 November 10
      - Background materials (Folder 189: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 189: 9)
    - On Michael McGwire's article in Review, about "SDI: The Ultimate Umbrella and Gareev,", 1986 November 19
      - Background materials (Folder 189: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 189: 11)
    - "Can Democracies Carry on Secret Operations That Are Necessary to Preserve the Democracies?", 1986 December 7. (Folder 189: 12)
    - "Managing Nuclear Operations," chapter in Nuclear Operations and Command and Control, by Ashton B. Carter in association with Charles A Zraket and John Steinbruner, 1987 January
      - General (Folder 189: 13)
      - Correspondence (Folder 189: 14)
      - Outline (Folder 189: 15)
    - "Continuing Control as a Requirement for Deterring" (with Richard Brody), Brookings Institution, 1987 January
      - Typescript (Folder 189: 16)
      - Galley (Folder 189: 17)
      - Printed copy (Folder 189: 18)
    - "Note On Iraq, Terrorism and Territorial Expansion,", 1987 January 26. (Folder 189: 19)
    - "Public Confusion about Iran and Iraq,", 1987 January 26. (Folder 189: 20)
    - "U.S. Troops in the Center of Europe and Their Use Elsewhere in Defending NATO Interests,", 1987 January 27
      - Background materials (Folder 189: 21)
      - Typescript (Folder 189: 22)
    - "Current Cliches about the Iraq-Iran War and Assistance to Either Side,", 1987 February 4 (Box 190)
      - Background materials (Folder 190: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 190: 2)
    - "Preserving or Foreclosing the Option on Whether or not to Deploy the Option of Active Ballistic Missile Defense in the Foreseeable Future?", 1987 February 4
      - Background materials (Folder 190: 3)
      - Typescript (Folder 190: 4)
    - "Issues on Selective Offense,", 1987 February 18
      - Background materials (Folder 190: 5)
      - Typescript (Folder 190: 6)
    - "S.U. Selectivity, Prompt Comprehensive Destruction and the Supposed Unreality of Any Soviet Threat,", 1987 February 27. (Folder 190: 7)
    - "Recent Misunderstandings about Self-Defense Zones in Space,", 1987 March 2
      - Background materials (Folder 190: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 190: 9)
    - "How We Came to Be Less Able Than the Soviet Union to Defend, Attack, and Use Space Systems in Wartime,", 1987 March 7
      - Background materials (Folder 190: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 190: 11)
    - "Land Based INF in Europe, the 'Zero Option' and 'National Suicide',", 1987 April 6. (Folder 190: 12)
    - "Improving NATO Conventional Response, Selective Nuclear Response and Agreements on Conventional and Nuclear Arms: Thoughts on Strategy after Sam Nunn's Speech in Brussels, 1987 April 13, on Three Tracks for NATO,", 1987 April 20
      - Background materials (Folder 190: 13)
      - Correspondence (Folder 190: 14)
      - Typescript (Folder 190: 15)
    - "Soviet Options against France during Attacks on Iran or Turkey or the Federal Republic of Germany, etc. and French Options for Reply: Branching Contingencies,", 1987 May 7. (Folder 190: 16)
    - "Discontinuities, Breakthroughs and Cumulatively Revolutionary Gradual Change,", 1987 May 28. (Folder 190: 17)
    - "The Sensitivity to Median Inaccuracy of Both Military Effectiveness and Unintended Harm to Bystanders,", 1987 June 4. (Folder 190: 18)
    - "Comments on the Trees for Future Soviet Union Options Against France While Invading Federal Republic of Germany and Possible French Replies,", 1987 June 5
      - Background materials (Folder 190: 19)
      - Typescript (Folder 190: 20)
    - "On the Comparison of 1-KT Earth Penetrators with Surface Bursts against Silos,", 1987 June 8. (Folder 190: 21)
    - "Responsible French Command and Control,", 1987 June 8. (Folder 190: 22)
    - Outline for Albert Wohlstetter's introduction and possible comments on June 11th, June 11th, 1987 June 9. (Folder 190: 23)
    - "Swords without Shields," The National Interest, 1987 Summer. (Folder 190: 24)
    - "The Need to Rethink Strategy Now Patent in the Disarray Over INF, the Gulf, the Controls, etc.,", 1987 June 26
      - Background material (Folder 190: 25)
      - Notes and typescript (Folder 190: 26-27)
    - "Maggie Thatcher on MAD: A Footnote to 26 June Note on Rethinking Strategy,", 1987 June 29 (Box 191)
      - Background materials (Folder 191: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 191: 2)
    - "Points and Issues for the July 14, 1987 Commission Plenary,", 1987 June 30
      - Notes (Folder 191: 3)
      - Typescript (Folder 191: 4)
    - "Towards Arms Control and Assured Destruction from Gaither and Assured Survival of the U.S.: PSAC on 'Massive' Surprise Attack 1958,", 1987 July 20. (Folder 191: 5)
    - "Discriminate and Indiscriminate Attacks versus Silos in U.S. and S.U.,", 1987 August 12
      - Background materials (Folder 191: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 191: 7)
    - "How Do We Cope with the Problem of Improving Our Long-Term Strategy Without an Unlikely Increase in Budgets?", 1987 October 19. (Folder 191: 8)
    - "Properties a Military Strategy Must Have to Be Successful,", 1987 November. (Folder 191: 9)
    - Review of Sam Huntington, "For the Long Haul: A Strategy of Differentiated, Discriminate Deterrence,", 1987 November 4
      - Background materials (Folder 191: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 191: 11)
    - "On the Relative Decline in U.S. Power and Its Supposed Implications,", 1987 November 16
      - Background materials (Folder 191: 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 191: 13)
    - "Comment on a Recent Comparison of U.S. and Soviet Space Capabilities,", 1987 November 18. (Folder 191: 14)
    - Key points on the Latham piece in Armed Forces Journal, 1987 November, entitled "Space-Based Support of Military Operations,", 1987 November 18
      - Background materials (Folder 191: 15)
      - Typescript (Folder 191: 16)
    - "Defensive Defense and the Basic Trouble with Western Self-Constraints (or Normally Bilateral Constraints) on the West's Ability to Initiate Attack Without Suicide,", 1987 November 23. (Folder 191: 17)
    - "An Integrated Strategy for the Long Haul,", 1987 December 10. (Folder 191: 18)
    - "Discriminate or Indiscriminate Deterrence?", 1988 February 24
      - General (Folder 191: 19)
      - Background materials (Folder 191: 20)
      - Notes (Folder 191: 21)
      - Typescript (Folder 191: 22)
      - Reviews (Folder 191: 23)
    - "On Iraq,", 1988 March 7. (Folder 191: 24)
    - "The Purpose of Arms Agreements and the Problem of Proving Non-Compliance,", 1988 March 7. (Folder 191: 25)
    - "Some Familiar Bureaucratic Views on the 'Verification Problem' for Arms Agreements and Specifically for START,", 1988 March 11. (Folder 191: 26)
    - "Evidence of Violations Strong and Timely Enough to Bring U.S. Offsetting Response,", 1988 March 15. (Folder 191: 27)
    - "Intelligence and Timely Response to Various Potential START Violations: Military Costs and Consequences,", 1988 March 18. (Folder 191: 28)
    - "European Reactions to Discriminate Deterrence: Misreadings and Clarifications,", 1988 April 12. (Box-folder 192: 1)
    - "The Attack on Military Spending FY 75 and FY 89,", 1988 April 22
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 2)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 3)
    - "Answer To Kennedy's New York Review,", 1988 May 5
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 4)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 5)
    - "Overseas Reactions to Discriminate Deterrence,", 1988 May 5. (Folder 192: 6)
    - "Suggested Revision of FSH's May 2, 1988 Draft on Cruise Missiles,", 1988 May 9
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 8)
    - "The Mindlessness of the Standard Negotiating Process on Constraining Nuclear Weapons: The Case of Harassment Drones,", 1988 May 24. (Folder 192: 9)
    - "Why Precise Estimates of the Size and Growth Rates of GNP, of Defense Budgets and of the Defense Share of GNP Are of Critical Importance to Paul Kennedy, But Not to CILS,", 1988 May 25. (Folder 192: 10)
    - "Balancing Evidence: Quantity versus Quality in Paul Kennedy,", 1988 May 30. (Folder 192: 11)
    - "Growth Rates in the Centrally Planned Economies,", 1988 May 31
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 13)
    - "Mutual Superpower Decline, Arms Control and Detente,", 1988 May 31
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 14)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 15)
    - "Chinese GNP and Its Growth Rate: The Huge Uncertainties,", 1988 June 1
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 16)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 17)
    - "Kistiakowsky, the Missile Gap and 'Hard-Line Paranoia',", 1988 June 1
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 18)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 19)
    - "A Disarmament Race among the Allies to Solve the Burden-Sharing Problem,", 1988 June 3
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 20)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 21)
    - "The Changing View of U.S. Military Spending, Military Power and Economic Growth: Four Periods Since World War II,", 1988 June 6. (Folder 192: 22)
    - "UK Versus German Growth Rates and Military Spending,", 1988 June 6. (Folder 192: 23)
    - "Statistics on Inequality and Growth in Soviet Union,", 1988 June 9. (Folder 192: 24)
    - "Military R&D and the Supposed Engineer Shortage for Civilian R&D,", 1988 June 15. (Folder 192: 25)
    - "Forced Labor and Income In and Out of the Gulag: Makarenko,", 1988 June 23. (Folder 192: 26)
    - "Mutual Decline? Mutual Withdrawal?", 1988 July 1. (Folder 192: 27)
    - "Another Blue Ribbon Panel on Wartime Uses of Space?", 1988 August 2. (Folder 192: 28)
    - "Growth Rates Over Millennia: Tainter vs. Maddison,", 1988 August 2. (Folder 192: 29)
    - "Economic Growth, Instabilities and Military Withdrawal,", 1988 August 31
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 30)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 31)
    - "Absolute Measures of Change in GDP Per Capita and Relative Measurements of Military Power,", 1988 September 19. (Folder 192: 32)
    - "The Consumer Price Index (CPI), Non-Cash Benefits, Money Income Distributions and Poverty Levels,", 1988 September 19
      - Background materials (Folder 192: 33)
      - Typescript (Folder 192: 34)
    - "Verification and START: September 1988,", 1988 September 26. (Folder 192: 35)
    - "Economic Growth and the Distribution of Income,", 1988 September 27. (Folder 192: 36)
    - "Fashions in Theories of Growth and Military Spending,", 1988 September 28. (Folder 192: 37)
    - "How Evolutionary Theories of Economic Growth Which Relate Economic Aggregates to Changes in Micro-Economic Incentives Tend to Complement Each Other Rather Than Conflict,", 1988 October 6. (Box-folder 193: 1)
    - "Adjusting CPS Money Income to Persons to Include Benefits In-Kind,", 1988 October 7. (Folder 193: 2)
    - "Economic Growth in S.U., in U.S. and in the Other Market Industrial Countries: Past, Present, Prospects and Implications for Alliance Security,", 1988 October 13. (Folder 193: 3)
    - "Computer Viruses and Nets,", 1988 November 7
      - Background materials (Folder 193: 4)
      - Typescript (Folder 193: 5)
    - "Interactions of Military and Civilian Technologies and of Military Power and Economic Growth,", 1988 November 11. (Folder 193: 6)
    - "Comparing Income Distributions at the Low, Middle and High Ends,", 1988 December 27
      - Background materials (Folder 193: 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 193: 8)
    - "Susan Sanderson Says Military R&D Hurts Competitiveness,", 1989 January 4
      - Background materials (Folder 193: 9)
      - Typescript (Folder 193: 10)
    - "Current Arguments against Organizational Change,", 1989 March 14. (Folder 193: 11)
    - "The Delicate Balance 30 after Years,", 1989 April
      - Background materials (Folder 193: 12)
      - Notes and typescript (Folder 193: 13-16)
      - Review (Folder 193: 17)
    - "Lindsay July 26 and August 9 Briefings for NSC,", 1989 April 12. (Folder 193: 18)